Olawale A. Fakorede Full Stack Web Developer

Tinuala Street, Ibadan, 200129, Oyo, Nigeria. | +2348122422728, +2347041279647 | 4th March, 1996 | ayomidefakorede58@gmail.com

Summary

Meticulous I.T. Personnel with over 4 years of experience interaction with computer. Reviewed written records to verify and transcribe data fields into electronic database. Collaborated with supervisors and data entry operators to understand scope of data entry tasks, correct errors and improve standard operating procedures. Tireless in creating complete accurate records. Highly-motivated employee with desire to take on new challenges. Strong worth ethic, adaptability and exceptional interpersonal skills. Adapt at working effectively unsupervised and quickly mastering new skills. High-performing I.T. Personnel with integrity and leadership skills. Applies knowledge and abilities to positively impact on working on I.T. challenges that come my way. Flexible in different situations and dynamics conditions. Works great and well before deadlines. Presently a Full stack developer having different projects with the use of Javascript, React, creating servers and database.

Skills & Abilities

- Full Stack Development
- Frontend Web Development
- Project Management
- Programming
- · MS Office
- Data Entry
- Debugging & Error Verification
- Excel Expertise
- Typing Manuscripts
- Staff Assistance
- Mail Handling

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Backend Web Development
- Troubleshooting Equipment
- Audio Technologies
- System Installation
- Social Integration
- Technical Troubleshooting
- Documentation Skills
- Examination Filing
- Strategic Planning
- Customer Service

Experience

ASSISTANT TUTOR | LARVA ACADEMY OYO, NIGERIA. | AUGUST 2024 - TILL DATE

- Tutoring Javascript
- Tutoring ReactIs
- Personal/extra teaching with interested students.

I.T. TUTOR | ST' CATHERINE COLLEGE, IBADAN, OYO, NIGERIA. | AUGUST 2024 - TILL DATE

- Teaching tech skills to students.
- Teaching the basic of Frontend web development to students.
- Developing student in different computer based skills.

I.T. PERSONNEL (EXAMS & RECORDS OFFICER) | LARIKEN INTERNATIONAL COLLEGE, IBADAN, OYO, NIGERIA. | MARCH 2023 – SEPTEMBER 2023

- Editing and Formatting of examination questions for all subjects.
- Printing of examination questions for all candidates
- Preparing of Transcript testimonial reference letters and issuing of certificates.
- Documentations of every documents into students file and portal.
- Entry of students' details and management of school website and portal.
- Registering of student for both Internal and external examinations.

DATA ENTRY OPEARTOR | ETHICS & VALUE COOPERATE | 2022 - 2023

- Compiled data from source documents prior to data entry
- Input client's information into spreadsheets and company's database to provide leaders with quick access to essential client data.
- Analyzed and processed current data records to provide detailed report.
- Proofread and edit documents to correct errors.
- Adjusted settings for format, page layout and line spacing.

I.T/MEDIA OPERATOR | AAMAC | 2018 - TO DATE

- Prepare, edit, entry of data and project all necessary information for each program.
- Identify, diagnose and resolve problems with audio and media systems.

 Place microphones in specific locations to maximize audio quality

 Supervise crew of audio-video team members.
- Compressed, digitized and duplicate audio ad digital files. □ Installations of software.

FARM MANAGER | BOFAK FARMS | 2015 - 2017

- Manage the poultry farm, fish farm and other crops.
- Identify and resolve problems within the farms
- Make placement of workers with the farm
- Ensure proper record keeping of activities within the farm.

Education

WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE | 2024 | LARVA ACADEMY

Full Stack Development (HTML5, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACTJS, NEXTJS, NODE JS, EXPRESS, MONGODB etc.)

HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA | 2021 | FEDERAL COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE.

Major: Agricultural and Bio-Environmental Engineering

HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA | 2021 | FEDERAL COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE. \Box

Major: Agricultural and Bio-Environmental Engineering

Languages (Oral)

AFRIKAANS ENGLISH

First Language

Official/Compulsory Language

Accomplishments

- Promoted to Head of Exams and Records in less than 3 months after resumption due to my fast and reliable way of attending to work in my department.
- Promoted from Media Operator to Head of I.T. & Media in less than 12-months with the achievements of putting different resources in place.
- Preserved an accuracy of 95% during 2 years of employment.

- Consistency maintained high customer satisfaction ratings.
- Awards as outstanding Student Union Government president of the year 2020.
- Awards of Exemplary Leadership in year 2020. ☐ Award of service.

Hobbies

- Working on a computer
- Surfing and researching from the internet.
- Programming and coding.
- Data Entry
- Formatting of documents.
- Listening to music
- Playing Games